A Guide to the Papers of Ambrose Bierce, 1842-1914
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- General Correspondence
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1893 MAY 1, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Enclosure: Invoice 1893 APR 25
      Re: "Black Beetles"
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger: Statement of Account re: "Black Beetles" 1893 MAY 7, TDS (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1893 AUG 7, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1893 AUG 10, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1893 AUG 25, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Edward A. Steele to his mother 1893 SEP 21, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1893 DEC 14, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mr. Peterson 1893 DEC 25, ALS. 2 p. (Box 2)
  - Letter from Stone & Kimball to E[dward] L.G. Steele 1894 FEB 5, TLS. 1 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington [1894 FEB 12], ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1894 FEB 27, ALS. 2 p.w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1894 MAR 5, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to Ambrose Bierce 1894 APR 18, ALS. 1 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1894 APR 24, ALS. 3 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1894 MAY 16, ALS. 2 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Royalty transmittal, United States Book Company to E.L.G. Steele 1894 MAY 16, DS. 1 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1894 MAY 22, ALS. 2 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele 1894 JUN 10, ALS. 2 p. (Box 3)
    - Enclosure: Receipt: Ambrose Bierce to E.L.G. Steele 1894 JUN 2, 1 p.
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1894 JUN 18, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1894 JUN 20, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from E[dward] L.G. Steele to his wife 1894 JUN 27, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1894 JUL 3, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mr. Goldsmith 1894 AUG 9, ALS. 1 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mrs. [E.L.G.] Steele 1894 AUG 29, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1894 SEP 30, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1894 OCT 15, ALS. 3 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Gustaz A. Danziger: bill of sale for all rights to "Black Beetles in Amber" 1894 OCT 23, ADS. 2 p. w/ docket (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mrs. [E.L.G.] Steele 1894 OCT 28, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington [1894 NOV 12], ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mr. [S.E.] Moffett 1894 DEC 10, ALS. 2 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mrs. [E.L.G.] Steele [ca. 1894 ], ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1895 FEB 3, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Leigh Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1895 FEB 13, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1895 FEB 19, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [S.E.] Moffett 1895 FEB 23, ALS. 2 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Leigh Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1895 FEB 25, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1895 APR 13, ALS. 5 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to S.E. Moffett 1895 APR 23, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
    - Enclosure: Jay J. Armstrong to Ambrose Bierce 1895 APR 13, ALS. 1 p.
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington [1895 JUN 12], ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to Carroll M. Carrington 1895 JUN 26, ALS. 5 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1895 JUL 13, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Lily [Walsh] to Ambrose [ Bierce] 1895 JUL 23, ALS. 8 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1895 AUG 26, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1895 SEP 19, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll M. Carrington 1895 OCT 19, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll M. Carrington 1895 OCT 27, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington, 4 p. w/ env. 1895 NOV 3, ALS (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll M. Carrington 1895 NOV 6, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Miriam Gallison 1895 NOV 20, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1895 DEC 2, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Miriam Gallison 1895 DEC 4, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington [1895 DEC 16], ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1896 JAN 14, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1896 JAN 17, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to C[arroll] M. Carrington 1896 MAR 8, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC to Harriet Hershberg, [Oakland CA] 1896 APR 27, ALS. 3 p. (Box 3)
    Bierce promises to have his photograph taken so that he can fulfill her request for an autograph and photograph and playfully says, "When I get there I shall blindfold you, hypnotize you and command you to find my lost youth and freedom. Then I shall marry you alive and live happily ever after." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1896 MAY 19, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
    Bierce writes "I am sending you by this mail the photograph of a bad old man with a scowl. The scowl, however, is not for you - you never saw it." He did not send a photograph to her big sister (Louise?) because she already had one more pleasant looking. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll M. Carrington 1896 JUN 25, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Oakland CA to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA [1897 JAN 16], ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
    Bierce accepts her gratitude and regard for himself although he does not believe that he merits it. He regrets that he cannot say when he will be able to meet Mr. King but agrees to see him informally some time when he is in Oakland. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Los Gatos CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1897 FEB 23, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
    Bierce sends Harriet some wild pansies growing by the wayside because they made him think of her, "I feel sure that the thought of you was put into my head by some divine intervention in the affairs of mortals, and for some purpose. My interpretation - with my feeble light and dull intuition- is that I am to send you some of those poor little frail pansies." He then goes on to explain that pansies are for thoughts and their old English name "hearts-ease" is better suited than "pansies = pensees" [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington [1897 MAR 16], ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington [1897 APR 1], ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 MAY 24, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Edward S. Kaufman to Mrs. E.L.G. Steele 1897 MAY 25, ALS. 1 p. w/ [mismatched] env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 MAY 26, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 JUN 30, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 JUL 4, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Los Gatos CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1897 JUL 11, ALS. 5 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
    Bierce thanks her for sending him the ginger cakes which he tried to share with the horned-toads but they preferred grasshoppers. He declines to visit Oakland because his last visit cost him a month's illness but urges her to visit him in Los Gatos and to bring with her "that impossible paragon, the Pittsburgh sister - whom, however, I believe to be a myth." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 JUL 11, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 JUL 21, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 JUL 27, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 AUG 8, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Edward S. Kaufman to Ambrose Bierce 1897 AUG 13, ALS. 1 p. (Box 3)
    - Enclosure: Postcard from John M. Forbes to Ambrose Bierce. 1897 AUG 11
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 AUG 14, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington [1897 SEP 12], ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Edward [L.G.] Steele 1897 SEP 14, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Los Gatos CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1897 SEP 19, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
    Bierce asks Harriet for the Paris address of her "musical sweetheart," Will King, so that he can thank him for a book and asks her to write him concerning herself. Otherwise he will have to hire a detective to shadow her night and day and send him reports of everything he learns about her activities. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 OCT 17, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 OCT 19, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 OCT 21, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Edward [L.G.] Steele 1897 NOV 13, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 NOV 1, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington [1897 NOV 15], ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Carroll M.] Carrington [c. 1897 NOV], ALS. 3 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Thorvald Solberg (Registrar of copyrights) to Edward L.G. Steele 1897 DEC 2, TLS. 1 p. w/ [mismatched] env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington [1897 DEC 7], ALS. 5 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from [c. 1897 DEC 7] Ambrose Bierce to [Carroll [M.] Carrington, ALS. 2 p. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Thorvald Solberg (Registrar of copyrights) to Edward L.G. Steele 1897 DEC 8, APC (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1897 DEC 22, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 FEB 1, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Los Gatos CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1898 FEB 11, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce wishes to see her very badly but remembers all too well the last illness which he suffered in Oakland, promises to send tickets to Belle and her if they will visit him in Los Gatos for a Sunday afternoon, and mentions receiving a letter from her sister Louise. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 FEB 11, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington [1898 FEB 28], ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Los Gatos CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Preston School, Waterman CA 1898 MAR 7, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce expresses joy at the receipt of her letter for "it clears you of the solemn suspicion of running away from me in cold-blooded infraction of our understanding" but he also thinks "it very rascally of you to take all the sunshine out of Oakland to bestow it upon Iona." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 MAR 7, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 MAR 14, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 MAR 24, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 MAR 31, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Los Gatos CA, to Harriet Hershberg 1898 APR 5, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
    Sends another photograph to replace the damaged one along with several books to "the Colonel and the Major" and mentions a letter from Mamie who proved to be a charming traveling companion. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 APR 6, ALS. 7 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 APR 29, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Los Gatos CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Waterman CA 1898 MAY 1, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Responding to her impression of his goodness Bierce writes, "It is pretty easy to be good to you, and I don't expect any credit for it in the books of the Recording Angel. He will say: 'Bah ! who wouldn't be good to Hattie Hershberg?' and then he will debit me with one selfish motive." He also mentions Kodak photographs of a group consisting of Hattie, Mamie, Dave, Selma, Louise, and himself, while assuring her of his devotion, "you are still the only girl in the world; and if there is a man who does not love you he is a scoundrel." Referring to his experience in military life Bierce writes, "No, my pet scheme for making soldiers of the Major's little rascals is not practicable. The confounded Government is so particular about the moral character of its recruits that I couldn't enlist myself. This is a great disappointment to me. I had quite set my heart on getting Co. A into Cuba, to prove that bad boys make the best soldiers. But I'm assured that it cannot be done." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 MAY 1, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington [1898 MAY 4], ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 [MAY] 5, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    [misdated "April" in letter] [#5992]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 MAY 16, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1898 JUN 15, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce writes that he has severed all connections with Los Gatos and that his health is good as he day dreams under the redwoods. He complains that thoughts of her often break in upon his reminiscences of the past, "Only the other day you wantonly interrupted the march of a column of troops from Readyville to Woodbury, Tennessee, which was not at all nice of you." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 JUN 22, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 JUN 28, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1898 JUL 6, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce agrees to take her to see the soldiers and to expound every military mystery they encounter and to plan a trip to the country when she visits. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA [1898 JUL 18], ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce promises to visit San Francisco next Sunday and Monday if she promises to give him Monday, when they can see the soldiers or go anywhere she wants. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1898 AUG 7, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce was unable to go to Oakland and wishes that he could run the world awhile, "My first official act would be to order you and Mamie to Los Gatos; my second, to go there myself." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 AUG 15, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 AUG 21, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    - Enclosure: "A Konstant Reader" to Bierce 1898 AUG 15, ALS. 2 p.
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wrights, California, to Belle Hershberg, Oakland, CA 1898 AUG 30, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce declines a guided tour of Silver Lake due to his poor health and continues by teasing Belle about her younger sister, "I'm thinking seriously of transferring my love from Hattie to you. You don't move away without notice, and - well, your mother's right in worrying about Hattie. That girl needs a convent worse than Selma - a convent with more austere 'sisters' and higher walls, topped with broken glass. A sentinel with a repeating rifle might be added." [#5992-p]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1898 SEP 15, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce thanks Hattie for the present of a cushion because it signified her return from her trip to a lake in the mountains and asks if he can visit her on Saturday afternoon. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 SEP 27, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 OCT 30, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1898 NOV 7, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce hopes that she is happier than in her last letter and asks individually about the health of her whole family. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Oakland CA 1898 NOV 20, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce agrees to examine the manuscript of one of her friends if it is in typescript and legible and describes his new quarters in a house with six rooms, one of which he has reserved for her and her chaperon if she will visit. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1898 DEC 7, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's, California, to Elbert Hubbard 1899 JAN 19, ALS. 2 p. (Box 4)
    Birece thanks Hubbard (1856-1915) for sending him a bound volume of The Philistine, a monthly magazine (1895-1915), and congratulates him on his success with the venture; Hubbard, an American inspirational essayist who published and edited The Philistine, saw its circulation increase from 2500 copies given away to 225,000 paid subscriptions. [#5992-o]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1899 FEB 26, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce apologizes for his seeming inattention and answers her questions about the Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington [1899 FEB], ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    - Enclosure: "A Social Success by Our Special Commissioner" n.d., AM. 4 p.
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1899 MAR 11, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Thomas Hutchinson 1899 MAR 18, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1899 MAR 22, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to Carroll Carrington 1899 MAR 24, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Herman Scheffauer to Carroll Carrington 1899 MAR 26, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to Carroll Carrington [1899 APR 7], ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Edward Steele 1899 APR 10, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    [ #5992-b]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1899 MAY 4, ALS. 5 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce urges Hattie to come, rent a house, and visit several weeks along with Belle and Florence, "Please say if you will come and thereby sweeten the fragrance of the flowers, intensify the gold of the sunshine and add a new music to the voices of my pet quails - one of which sits on my knee as I write and looks knowing as if he said: I can tell by your face whom you are writing to?" [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Waterman CA 1899 JUN 25, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce expresses his disappointment that she did not come up to visit during her summer outing and determines to accustom himself to disappointment even to the point of allowing Harriet, Belle, and Florence to marry if they choose. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1899 AUG 2, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1899 AUG 17, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1899 SEP 10, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce asks her to again send the recipe for molasses candy for some of the ladies there want to make some and "as the purpose of my existence is to please the members of the sex which your virtues preserve from damnation I comply with the request." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1899 SEP 19, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington [1899] SEP 21, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1899 OCT 3, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, Waterman CA 1899 OCT 22, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce voices his concern over Louise's illness (malaria ?) and begs for news of her condition. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1899 OCT 22, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1899 OCT 24, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1899 NOV 24, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce asks for news of Louise. Relates plans to make a farewell visit to San Francisco before he returns to Washington DC to live. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1899 NOV 27, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce thanks Hattie for her good news about Louise and the invitation to Thanksgiving dinner which he must decline in the chaos of preparing to leave for Washington DC but promises to try to see them all before he leaves. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Wright's CA, to S.G. Blythe, Editor of Cosmopolitan Magazine 1899 NOV 27, ALS. 2 p. (Box 4)
    Replying to Blythe's letter of the sixth, Bierce informs him that he has not written any fiction recently and has "uniformly declined to write for the magazines, being dissatisfied with the indefinite character of their proposals and the uncertainty as to when the work if accepted will be published." He admits that the Cosmopolitan Magazine may have a different system of publication than most magazines and declares it to be better than the majority of them. [#5992-m]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1899 DEC 8, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1899 DEC 27, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, The Lick House, to Harriet Hershberg, [San Francisco CA] [1899 DEC ?], ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce tells Hattie that he is to leave today and asks if she can keep herself and Louise and Belle at home long enough to see him before he leaves at 5 p.m. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1900 JAN 21, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)